Kenny Bean

Computer Science Professional

Summary

Hardworking, creative computer science professional with internship experience of 1.5 years. Seeking to start an ambitious career within a company that will provide new experiences and the opportunity for advancement and exposure to cutting edge computing technology.

Employment

Working Student

September, 2016-Present

Autoliv-Nissin Brake Systems, Southfield, MI

- Created hardware in the loop (HIL) set ups.
- Ran multiple kinds of tests based on specifications given by engineers.
- Wrote data visualization/report generation software for the HIL in Matlab's App Designer.
- Worked in a CarSim and dSpace Environment.
- Modified the dSPACE environment to meet the specifications given by algorithm engineer.
- Created temperature and current gauge to prevent damage to the ECU on HIL bench during testing.

Server

June, 2014-December, 2016

Red Robin Gourmet Burgers, Madison Heights, MI

- Tended to the needs of guests.
- Completed additional tasks executed around the restaurant given to me by managers.
- Trusted with the negotiation of disgruntled guests.
- Received numerous good reviews/ comments about my service.

Education

- Bachelors in Science, 2014-2018, Software Engineering, University of Michigan-Dearborn, MI
 - **GPA:** 3.4
 - Preferred area of study: Website Technologies
 - UPE Honors Society Member
- High School Diploma, 2010-2014, General Studies, Hazel Park High School, MI
 - **GPA:** 3.75
 - National Honors Society Member

Personal Info

Email: ksbean@umich.edu
Phone: (248) 808-1437
Graduation Date: April, 2018

Website: https://ksbean.github.io/

Key Skills

Website Design
Testing (HIL environment)
Customer Interaction
Technical Writing Experience

Language Experience

C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Python, Scheme, Prolog, Lisp, Visual Basic, Assembly, HTML5, XML, CSS3

Interests and Passion

Created and currently maintain personal website.

Currently working on home automation using raspberry pi and AIY voice kit.

Wish to learn more about server side and backend website programming.



Skills

- Hardware/Embedded Platforms
 - Microcontroller:

Arduino, TMS 570

• GPU/Microprocessor:

Raspberry Pi

- Software Process Experience
 - Process Models:

Waterfall, Rapid Prototyping, Agile (Scrum, Extreme Programming, etc.)

• Structural UML Diagrams:

Class, Component, Deployment

• Behavioral UML Diagrams:

Activity, Sequence, Use Case, State-Transition, Communication

• Industrial Exposure:

Scheduling/Tracking Performance Milestones, Understanding of Ordering Processes, Creation of Purchase Orders/Quotes IDE Familiarity

Visual Studio, Aptana, Eclipse, XAMPP, Atom

Automotive Specific

dSpace, CarSim, Matlab/Simulink, Vector CANape, Vehicle Network Toolbox, IPE motion

3-D Modeling

Maya, Unity, OpenGL

- Other Knowledge
 - Windows Office Enterprise:

Word, Excel, SharePoint, PowerPoint, etc.

- Testing Processes for Industry Standards:
 ISO 26262, ISO 9000, CMMI
- Design and Architecture:

Modern Database Architecture, Software Design/Architectural Patterns

Comprehension of Modern Brake Systems:
 Hydraulics, Sensor reading,
 Development of Algorithm